so there is a taxonomy called Flynn's
taxonomy of parallel machines it
distinguishes parallel machines
according to how many instruction
streams they have and how many data
streams these instructions operate on
the first type of machine is single
instructions single data or S SD and
logically this type of a machine
executes one instruction stream and each
instruction operates on one data stream
this is really your normal uni processor
so if we have for example a single core
machine that's what it is the next type
of machine is single instruction
multiple data so it executes one
instruction stream meaning there is one
program with a single program counter we
go through but there is more than one
data stream they operate on the most
common example of this used to be
so-called Vector processors which
execute a program but each instruction
instead of operating on normal scalar
values operates on vectors so for
example you can execute an add
instruction but it operates on two
source and one destination Vector of
things so it operates on many many data
items at a time modern processors also
have these multimedia extension
instructions such as MMX or sse1 123 and
they are also an example of limited simd
where a single multimedia instruction
will will operate on maybe four or eight
data items then you can have a multiple
instruction single data stream this is
weird because we have multiple
instruction streams so there are several
different programs executing at the same
time all operating on the same stream of
data so it's not used much and the
closest we get to this is something like
a stream processor where you have the
first processor operating on for example
the raw data from the camera and then
that data moves on to the next processor
which is going to process it some
further like find the edges or sharpen
it or something and so on but even there
it's not truly that we have a single
data stream because the output of the
first processor is not the same as the
raw camera feed so this is just kind of
the closest we get to it but really MISD
is not really used much and then we have
Mi IMD where there is more than one
instruction stream more than one data
stream and this would be your normal
multiprocessor where each processor has
its own program that it's running with
its own program counter and so on and
each of them operates on its own data so
they don't have to do things in loog
step to operate on the data and they
don't do something like a stream
processing so this type of processor
really includes most of the processors
you can buy today because most
processors today are multicore which
means really they have several processor
cores each of which executes its own
instruction stream and can access data
independently so it has multiple data
streams and this lesson is mostly about
this type of machines